Pablo Clark

pablo.clark.com.mx

Barcelona, Spain +34 655 167 941 pabloclarkd@gmail.com <u>Sociologist</u> with seven years of experience in research projects and web tools. I am an analytical thinker with knowledge of quantitative and qualitative methods, and an effective communicator with an eye for detail.

Work experience

May 2022 - present

Online Data Analyst – Telus International

Analyze and provide feedback on text, web pages, images and other types of information for leading search engines.

2019 - May 2022

Researcher - Instituto Mexicano para la Competitividad A.C.

Led public policy analysis projects in topics such as higher education economic <u>returns</u>, school choice, and women in STEM

Managed development of a website and maintained two other web tools, coordinating the work of the developer, analyst and communications teams

Analyzed data and created visualizations to answer research questions and turn insights into stories to communicate findings in reports, opinion articles, presentations and essays

Collected data from various sources and wrote scripts to transform it for use in relational databases

Wrote grant proposal, research reports and presentations and communication materials

Presented research findings to donors, clients, media and other stakeholders

2015 - 2019

Analyst - Instituto Mexicano para la Competitividad A.C.

Supported public policy research and applied interventions, including the planning and development of web tools.

including the planning and development of web tools

Used Google Analytics to monitor site usage, track objectives and suggest improvements

Managed contact and relationships with our website users

Education

2010 - 2015

Bachelor's degree in Sociology with honors from Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México.

Key skills

Data analysis and visualization in R
Writing grant proposals, research
reports, opinion articles, essays,
and communication materials
Microsoft Office (Word, Powerpoint,
Excel) & Google Workspace
Public speaking, interviews and
presentations
Project management
Native Spanish speaker and fluent in
English (TOELF iBT 112)

Other experience

Google Analytics

January 2020 – August 2020 **Teacher assistant - Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México**Teacher assistant in 'Applied statistics in the social

sciences II" course.